<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; Midspace Forum2021 Diglib</title>
	<atom:link href="https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 12:25:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>England’s ‘Bazball’ revolution faces ultimate test in Ashes</title>
		<link>https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/englands-bazball-revolution-faces-ultimate-test-in-ashes/</link>
					<comments>https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/englands-bazball-revolution-faces-ultimate-test-in-ashes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/?p=21</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Can England regain the Ashes playing their ultra-aggressive “Bazball” brand of cricket or will they come unstuck against battle-hardened Australia? The answer will come over the coming weeks, starting with the first Test of a hotly anticipated five-match series at Edgbaston today (Friday). England have forced the rest of the world to sit up and ... <a title="England’s ‘Bazball’ revolution faces ultimate test in Ashes" class="read-more" href="https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/englands-bazball-revolution-faces-ultimate-test-in-ashes/" aria-label="More on England’s ‘Bazball’ revolution faces ultimate test in Ashes">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Can England regain the Ashes playing their ultra-aggressive “Bazball” brand of cricket or will they come unstuck against battle-hardened Australia?</p>
<p>The answer will come over the coming weeks, starting with the first Test of a hotly anticipated five-match series at Edgbaston today (Friday).</p>
<p>England have forced the rest of the world to sit up and take notice, with 11 wins in 13 Tests since captain Ben Stokes and coach Brendon McCullum joined forces last year.</p>
<p>But doubts persist as to whether their policy of all-out attack can work against arch-rivals Australia, who only last week hammered India by 209 runs at The Oval to win the World Test Championship final.</p>
<p>Steve Waugh, the last Australia captain to win an Ashes series in England, back in 2001, is not alone in questioning whether Stokes’s side have an alternative plan.</p>
<p>“Have they got a Plan B?” Waugh said to the Australian media. “They have shown they are good enough to carry this style of cricket off but the ultimate test will be against a world-class bowling attack, which Australia has got.”</p>
<p>England had won just one out of 17 Tests before newly appointed English cricket chief Rob Key brought McCullum and Stokes together to oversee a dynamic revamp of their long-format game dubbed “Bazball”, in reference to the nickname of former New Zealand captain McCullum.</p>
<p>And all-rounder Stokes is adamant he has no intention of altering his approach.</p>
<div id="8cd7c3dd-1bc4-41c9-a231-2429b2c3d12d">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS KMFZK qwBlA">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p>“Nothing is going to change because we’ve had unbelievable success with it,” the 32-year-old told the BBC.</p>
<p>“If we were to change anything from the last 12 months because we find ourselves in an Ashes series then anything from the last 12 months will have been completely pointless.”</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="7f10aca5-f78e-47d1-923b-f8c296cd4470">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS KMFZK qwBlA">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-title">
<h2>Strike rate</h2>
</div>
</div>
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p>England have scored at an eye-watering 4.85 runs an over in the past year.</p>
<p>And England great James Anderson, Test cricket’s most successful paceman, said that had benefits for the bowlers as well.</p>
<p>“The (bowling) run-rate is irrelevant to Ben in particular,” explained Anderson.</p>
<p>“He’s like ‘I don’t care how many runs you go for, I want 20 wickets as quickly as possible’. You’re constantly thinking, as a bowler then, about ‘How am I taking my next wicket’?”</p>
<div id="7f10aca5-f78e-47d1-923b-f8c296cd4470">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS KMFZK qwBlA">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p>Of more immediate concern to England fans than Stokes’s philosophy is his fitness.</p>
<p>Stokes, a lively seamer, opted against bowling himself in England’s recent 10-wicket win over Ireland after struggling with a knee injury.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="08537a8c-581f-4f46-ad2d-2d7d5330c439">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS KMFZK qwBlA">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p>He has since declared himself fit to bowl and with Anderson and fellow paceman Ollie Robinson suffering niggling injuries, the hosts will hope he can make good on those words.</p>
<p>England will be without Jack Leach for the whole Ashes after the left-arm spinner was ruled out with a back problem.</p>
<p>Moeen Ali has been recalled in his absence and the off-spinner’s two-year Test retirement could end at his Edgbaston home ground, even though he averages an expensive 64.65 in Ashes cricket.</p>
<p>Ashes-holders Australia, by contrast, have a proven world-class off-spinner in Nathan Lyon, who is closing in on 500 Test wickets.</p>
<p>Captain Pat Cummins is in the fortunate position of deciding if either Mitchell Starc or Josh Hazlewood joins him in a fast-bowling attack likely to include Scott Boland.</p>
<div id="d35882ae-f3a2-447a-9f0c-e5b14a59521d">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS qwBlA">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p>Boland’s fine WTC final display – he took five wickets in the match – left him with 33 wickets in eight Tests at a miserly average of 14.57.</p>
<p>Second-ranked Australia drew the last Ashes series in England in 2019 2-2 and demolished the old enemy 4-0 on home turf in 2021/22.</p>
<p>But they have not won a series in England for 22 years, with many of their batsmen, the outstanding Steve Smith excepted, struggling to adapt to English conditions.</p>
<p>Australia have now gone 12 Test innings in England since enjoying a first-wicket stand of 20 or more, while under-pressure opener David Warner, 36, has now managed just one century in his past 34 Test innings against all opponents.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="2b576eb2-865f-4130-b1f6-d6672ac45809">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS qwBlA">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p>His battle with his nemesis, paceman Stuart Broad, will be just one of a number of fascinating subplots, with Tests at Lord’s, Headingley, Old Trafford and The Oval to follow the curtainraiser in Birmingham.</p>
<p>“An Ashes (in England) is bloody hard to win. It’s been 20-odd years so it’s not going to be easy,” said the 30-year-old Cummins. “If we win, that is legacy-defining stuff.”</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/englands-bazball-revolution-faces-ultimate-test-in-ashes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ton-up Root revives England before Stokes declares in 1st Test</title>
		<link>https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/ton-up-root-revives-england-before-stokes-declares-in-1st-test/</link>
					<comments>https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/ton-up-root-revives-england-before-stokes-declares-in-1st-test/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joe Root ended his Ashes century-drought as England made 393-8 before skipper Ben Stokes&#8217;s bold declaration on the opening day of the first Test against Australia at Edgbaston on Friday. England were in danger of squandering the advantage of winning the toss on a good pitch as they fell to 176-5 after losing two wickets in quick ... <a title="Ton-up Root revives England before Stokes declares in 1st Test" class="read-more" href="https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/ton-up-root-revives-england-before-stokes-declares-in-1st-test/" aria-label="More on Ton-up Root revives England before Stokes declares in 1st Test">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Root ended his Ashes century-drought as England made 393-8 before skipper Ben Stokes&#8217;s bold declaration on the opening day of the first Test against Australia at Edgbaston on Friday.</p>
<p>England were in danger of squandering the advantage of winning the toss on a good pitch as they fell to 176-5 after losing two wickets in quick succession.</p>
<p>But former England captain Root was 118 not out &#8212; the 32-year-old&#8217;s first Ashes hundred in eight years and 17 Tests &#8212; when Stokes called a halt to give his side 20 minutes&#8217; bowling against Australia before the close.</p>
<p>In the corresponding Ashes campaign four years ago, Australia opener David Warner averaged a meagre 9.50 in 10 innings and was dismissed seven times by veteran England bowler Stuart Broad.</p>
<p>But despite Broad taking the new ball on Friday, Warner survived to be eight not out in a total of 14-0 at stumps.</p>
<p>Earlier, Root received excellent support from Yorkshire team-mate Jonny Bairstow, who made a run-a-ball 78 during a sixth-wicket partnership of 121.</p>
<p>Australia&#8217;s Nathan Lyon was taunted by sections of a capacity 25,000 crowd.</p>
<p>But he still took 4-149 as he moved to within nine wickets of 500 in Tests after bowling 29 overs &#8212; an unusually high number for an off-spinner on the first day of a Test.</p>
<p>England have won 11 of their last 13 Tests, with an aggressive approach, dubbed &#8216;Bazball&#8217; in reference to coach Brendon McCullum&#8217;s nickname, exemplified by the aggressive batting that was a hallmark of Bairstow&#8217;s irun-a-ball innings.</p>
<p>&#8220;It hasn&#8217;t changed over the last 12 months,&#8221; Bairstow told Sky Sports of Englad&#8217;s approach. &#8220;If the ball is there to hit we have tried to hit it. If we miss, it&#8217;s part and parcel of the game.&#8221;</p>
<div id="5e5c5ead-1a0b-4f68-bf79-8ad3cf0f9636">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS qwBlA">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-title">
<h2>&#8216;Special times&#8217;</h2>
</div>
</div>
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p>Bairstow and Root both hit hundreds during a match-clinching stand of 269 against India at Edgbaston last year, with Bairstow compiling centuries in both innings of a seven-wicket win.</p>
<p>As for his latest big partnership with Root, the wicketkeeper added: &#8220;We were five down and thinking &#8216;lose a couple here and we are in trouble&#8217;. But I&#8217;ve been lucky enough to bat with Rooty for far too long. We&#8217;ve shared some special times in the middle.&#8221;</p>
<p>England signalled their intentions from Friday&#8217;s first ball, with Zak Crawley driving Australia captain Pat Cummins through the covers for four in elegant fashion.</p>
<p>But recently-crowned World Test champions Australia, hit back when Ben Duckett (12) was caught behind off recalled paceman Josh Hazlewood.</p>
<p>And Crawley fell for 61 off what became the last ball of the session, when paceman Scott Boland produced a superb delivery that leapt off a length and brushed the glove, with England 124-3 at lunch.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="b82d0afa-b0b6-4ca4-b66a-4ded5859b280">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS KMFZK qwBlA">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p>Harry Brook was out for 32 in bizarre fashion when he shouldered arms to Lyon, with the ball looping off the thigh pad and spinning into the stumps after Brook had lost sight of it.</p>
<p>Stokes then lasted just eight balls, caught behind on the drive off Hazlewood.</p>
<p>Australia thought they had the prized wicket of Root when he was given out lbw to Lyon, but the batsman&#8217;s immediate review confirmed he had gloved the ball.</p>
<p>Bairstow thrashed Hazlewood for four.</p>
<p>But having been dropped by a diving Alex Carey on 68, Bairstow was dismissed when he charged at Lyon only to be stumped.</p>
<p>Moeen Ali, in his first Test for nearly two years since retiring from red-ball cricket, had made 18 when, just like Bairstow, he was needlessly stumped off Lyon.</p>
<p>Root, who reverse swept both Boland and Cummins for extraordinary sixes, however, took a single off Lyon to complete a 145-ball hundred that included seven fours.</p>
<p>England are bidding for a first Ashes series win since 2015, with Australia aiming for a first Ashes campaign victory in England in 22 years.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/ton-up-root-revives-england-before-stokes-declares-in-1st-test/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Records tumble in Bangladesh’s Afghan thrashing in Dhaka Test</title>
		<link>https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/records-tumble-in-bangladeshs-afghan-thrashing-in-dhaka-test/</link>
					<comments>https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/records-tumble-in-bangladeshs-afghan-thrashing-in-dhaka-test/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 12:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bangladesh’s win over Afghanistan in the Dhaka Test dominance personified. The Tigers took control of the contest from the first session of Day 1, enhanced their control over the next two days, before finishing off the job in the morning session of Day 4. The mammoth margin of the victory has made it one of ... <a title="Records tumble in Bangladesh’s Afghan thrashing in Dhaka Test" class="read-more" href="https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/records-tumble-in-bangladeshs-afghan-thrashing-in-dhaka-test/" aria-label="More on Records tumble in Bangladesh’s Afghan thrashing in Dhaka Test">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh’s win over Afghanistan in the Dhaka Test dominance personified. The Tigers took control of the contest from the first session of Day 1, enhanced their control over the next two days, before finishing off the job in the morning session of Day 4. The mammoth margin of the victory has made it one of the most memorable victories ever in Bangladesh’s Test history. With the victory, Liton Das and his men have also shattered a number of records, some of which were in place for around a century.</p>
<p><strong>546–</strong> Bangladesh won the Dhaka Test against Afghanistan by 546 runs, which is their biggest win in Tests in terms of runs. Their previous biggest win was a 226-run win against Zimbabwe in Chattogram back in 2005.</p>
<p><strong>89–</strong> Bangladesh’s win over Afghanistan is the biggest victory in Tests in terms of runs in the past 89 years. The last time a team won a Test with a margin of an excess of 546 was way back in 1934, when Australia pummeled England by 562 runs at the Oval in London.</p>
<p><strong>3–</strong> Bangladesh’s win over Afghanistan is the third highest victory in Test history in terms of runs. With the win, the Tigers overtook Australia’s 530-run win over South Africa in 1911. This is also the largest win in Test cricket in the current millennium. Earlier, the biggest win since the 2000s belonged to South Africa, who thrashed Australia by 492 runs in Johannesburg in 2018.</p>
<p><strong>1–</strong> This is the largest win in terms of runs for an Asian team in Test history. Earlier, the record belonged to Sri Lanka, who had handed Bangladesh a 465-run defeat in Chattogram back in 2009. This is also the biggest Test win in Asian soil.</p>
<div id="1deeb660-6b12-4992-9ff9-2d5c476d008f">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS KMFZK qwBlA">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p><strong>200–</strong> Afghanistan got bundled out for 146 and 115 in the two innings of the Dhaka Test. This is the first time Bangladesh have bowled out a team twice in a Test match for a score below 200.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="f6423a91-5d7b-474b-9bff-1431561ba31c">
<div class="storyCard eyOoS qwBlA">
<div class="   
                  story-element"></p>
<div class="story-element story-element-text">
<div>
<p><strong>50–</strong> Afghanistan batted for 39 overs in the first innings and 33 overs in the second innings at the Sher-e-Bangla National Cricket Stadium in Dhaka. This is the first time a team has played less than 50 overs in both innings of a Test against the Tigers.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://midspace.forum2021.diglib.org/2023/06/17/records-tumble-in-bangladeshs-afghan-thrashing-in-dhaka-test/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
